<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
         xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
         xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#"
         xmlns:sosa="http://www.w3.org/ns/sosa/">

  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://www.w3.org/ns/sosa/isHostedBy">
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">in platform</rdfs:label>
  </rdf:Description>

  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://www.w3.org/ns/sosa/hosts">
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">has instrument</rdfs:label>
  </rdf:Description>

  <skos:Collection rdf:about="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Instrument">
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://purl.org/iso25964/skos-thes#ConceptGroup"/>
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Instrument</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">TBW</skos:definition>

    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Instrument/SAR-C">
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">SAR-C</skos:prefLabel>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Sentinel-1A"/>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Sentinel-1B"/>
        <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Sentinel-1A"/>
        <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Sentinel-1B"/>
        <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Instrument_Modes/SM"/>
        <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Instrument_Modes/IW"/>
        <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Instrument_Modes/EW"/>
        <skos:narrower rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Instrument_Modes/WV"/>
        <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">C-SAR</skos:altLabel>
        <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Synthetic Aperture Radar (C-band)</skos:altLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The C-SAR instrument is an active phased array antenna providing fast scanning in elevation (to cover the large range of incidence angle and to support ScanSAR operation) and in azimuth (to allow use of TOPS technique to meet the required image performance). To meet the polarisation requirements, it has dual channel transmit and receive modules and H/V-polarised pairs of slotted waveguides. It has an internal calibration scheme, where transmit signals are routed into the receiver to allow monitoring of amplitude/phase to facilitate high radiometric stability. SENTINEL-1's metallised carbon-fibre-reinforced-plastic radiating waveguides ensure good radiometric stability even though these elements are not covered by the internal calibration scheme. The digital chirp generator and selectable receive filter bandwidths allow efficient use of on-board storage considering the ground range resolution dependence on incidence angle. Group: Instrument_Details Entry_ID: SENTINEL-1 C-SAR Group: Instrument_Identification Instrument_Category: Earth Remote Sensing Instruments Instrument_Class: Active Remote Sensing Instrument_Type: Imaging Radars Short_Name: C-SAR Long_Name: C-Band Synthetic Aperture Radar End_Group Group: Associated_Platforms Short_Name: SENTINEL-1 End_Group Online_Resource: https://sentinel.esa.int/web/sentinel/sentinel-1-sar-wiki/-/wiki/Sentinel%20One/Instrument Creation_Date: 2015-02-05 End_Group</skos:definition>
        <rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="https://sentinels.copernicus.eu/web/sentinel/user-guides/sentinel-1-sar"/>
        <rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="http://www.wmo-sat.info/oscar/instruments/view/sar_c_sentinel_1"/>
        <skos:exactMatch rdf:resource="https://gcmdservices.gsfc.nasa.gov/kms/concept/ed400e7c-229e-48be-9a93-84f2fc864448"/>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>
  
    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Instrument/MSI">
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">MSI</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Multi-Spectral Imager for Sentinel-2</skos:altLabel>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Sentinel-2A"/>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Sentinel-2B"/>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The instrument is based on the pushbroom observation concept. The telescope features a TMA (Three Mirror Anastigmat) design with a pupil diameter of 150 mm, providing a very good imaging quality all across its wide FOV (Field of View). The equivalent swath width is 290 km. The telescope structure and the mirrors are made of silicon carbide (SiC) which allows to minimize thermoelastic deformations. The VNIR focal plane is based on monolithic CMOS (Complementary Metal Oxide Semiconductor) detectors while the SWIR focal plane is based on a MCT (Mercury Cadmium Telluride) detector hybridized on a CMOS read-out circuit. A dichroic beamsplitter provides the spectral separation of VNIR and SWIR channels. EADS Astrium SAS of Toulouse is prime for the instrument. The industrial core team also comprises Jena Optronik (Germany), Boostec (Bazet, France), Sener and GMV (Spain), and AMOS, Belgium. The VNIR detectors are built by Astrium-E2V, while the French company Sofradir received a contract to provide the SWIR detectors for MSI. Calibration: A combination of partial on-board calibration with a sun diffuser and vicarious calibration with ground targets is foreseen to guarantee a high quality radiometric performance. State-of-the-art lossy compression based on wavelet transform is applied to reduce the data volume. The compression ratio will be fine tuned for each spectral band to ensure that there is no significant impact on image quality. The observation data are digitized on 12 bit. A shutter mechanism is implemented to prevent the instrument from direct viewing of the sun in orbit and from contamination during launch. The average observation time per orbit is 16.3 minutes, while the peak value is 31 minutes (duty cycle of about 16-31%). Imager type Pushbroom instrument Spectral range (total of 13 bands) 0.4-2.4 µm (VNIR + SWIR) Spectral dispersion technique Dichroic for VNIR and SWIR split In field separation within focal plane Mirror dimensions of telescope M1 = 440 mm x 190 mm M2 = 145 mm x 118 mm M3 = 550 mm x 285 mm SSD (Spatial Sampling Distance) 10 m: (VNIR) B2, B3, B4, B8 (4 bands) 20 m: B5, B6, B7, B8a, B11, B12 (6 bands) 60 m: B1, B9, (3 bands) Swath width 290 km, FOV= 20.6º Detector technologies Monolithic Si (VNIR); hybrid HgCdTe CMOS (SWIR) Detector cooling Cooling of SWIR detector to &lt; 210 K Data quantization 12 bit Instrument mass, power ~ 290 kg, &lt; 266 W Data rate 450 Mbit/s after compression</skos:definition>
        <rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="https://www.wmo-sat.info/oscar/instruments/view/msi_sentinel_2a"/>
        <skos:exactMatch rdf:resource="https://gcmdservices.gsfc.nasa.gov/kms/concept/fc57a9a0-a287-4bcf-a517-20811b55596b"/>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>
  
    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Instrument/OLCI">
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">OLCI</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Ocean and Land Colour Imager</skos:altLabel>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Sentinel-3A"/>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Sentinel-3B"/>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The OLCI instrument baseline is the successor to ENVISAT MERIS with additional spectral channels, different camera arrangements and simplified on-board processing. The OLCI is a push-broom instrument with five camera modules sharing the field of view. The field of view of the five cameras is arranged in a fan-shaped configuration in the vertical plane, perpendicular to the platform velocity. Each camera has an individual field of view of 14.2° and a 0.6° overlap with its neighbours. The whole field of view is shifted across track by 12.6° away from the sun to minimise the impact of sun glint.</skos:definition>
        <rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="https://www.wmo-sat.info/oscar/instruments/view/olci"/>
        <rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="https://sentinel.esa.int/web/sentinel/technical-guides/sentinel-3-olci"/>
        <skos:exactMatch rdf:resource="https://gcmdservices.gsfc.nasa.gov/kms/concept/65ed042c-df53-4afb-8b6a-1ea16958015d"/>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>
  
    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Instrument/SLSTR">
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">SLSTR</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Sea and Land Surface Temperature Radiometer</skos:altLabel>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Sentinel-3A"/>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Sentinel-3B"/>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The principal aim of the SLSTR instrument mission on-board SENTINEL-3 is to maintain continuity with the (A)ATSR series of instruments. The design supports this by incorporating the basic functionality of AATSR, with the addition of some new, more advanced, features. These include a wider swath, new channels (including two channels dedicated to fire detection), and higher resolution in some channels.</skos:definition>
        <rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="https://sentinel.esa.int/web/sentinel/technical-guides/sentinel-3-slstr"/>
        <rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="https://www.wmo-sat.info/oscar/instruments/view/slstr"/>
        <skos:exactMatch rdf:resource="https://gcmdservices.gsfc.nasa.gov/kms/concept/7204c4d5-b7d0-41af-ba90-61d47c6dc610"/>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>
  
    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Instrument/MWR">
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">MWR</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Micro-Wave Radiometer</skos:altLabel>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Sentinel-3A"/>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Sentinel-3B"/>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">MWR is a nadir looking sounder, operating at 23.8 and 36.5 GHz (K/Ka-band) covering a bandwidth of 200 MHz in each channel. The objective is to provide water vapor and cloud water contents in the field of view of the altimeter, necessary to compensate for the propagation delay induced by these atmospheric components and affecting the radar measurements. Such corrections are only possible over the ocean, where the background noise is stable and can be quantified either by the 3rd (optional) radiometer channel, or derived from the altimeter measurements of the backscattered power. Alternatively, over ice and land surfaces where MWR data cannot be used, wet troposphere corrections will be derived based on global meteorological data and dedicated models. The MWR instrument is being developed by EADS CASA Espacio (ECE) under contract with Thales Alenia Space France (TAS-F) and ESA. MWR measures the thermal radiation emitted by Earth (brightness temperature). The received signal is proportional to the abundance of the atmospheric component emitted at the observed frequency and the sea-surface reflectivity. This information reveals the delay added to the altimeter pulses by moisture in the troposphere. The MWR instrument is comprised of the following part elements: antenna assembly, REU (Radiometer Electronics Units), the main structure and the thermal control hardware. Both K-band and Ka-band channels are fully redundant, except for the antenna assembly, with cold redundancy without cross-strapping. Center frequency, bandwidth 23.8 GHz, 200 MHz 36.5 GHz, 200 MHz Center frequency stability 180 kHz/ºC 220 kHz/ºC Radiometric performance Accuracy: &lt; 3K Sensitivity: 0.29 K Stability: &lt; 0.6 K Accuracy: &lt; 3K Sensitivity: 0.34 K Stability: &lt; 0.6 K Beam efficiency (2.5 HPBW) 94.1% 96.0% Antenna footprint diameter (average HPBW) 23.5 km 18.5 km Calibration cycle ~ 1 / hour Dicke frequency 78.5 Hz (nominal, programmable within 76-80 Hz range) Integration time 152.88 ms (nominal, within 150-157.9 ms range) Dynamic range 2.7 K to 320 K (radiometric performance guaranteed at 150 K - 313 K range) Side-lobe level (SLL) &lt; -36 dB &lt; -45 dB Antenna beam pointing Along-track: 1.98 Cross-track: 0.0º Along-track: 1.93º Cross-track: 0.0ºº Main antenna diameter 60 cm Instrument mass, power consumption ~25 kg, 34 W</skos:definition>
        <rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="https://sentinel.esa.int/web/sentinel/technical-guides/sentinel-3-altimetry/instrument/mwr"/>
        <rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="https://www.wmo-sat.info/oscar/instruments/view/mwr_sentinel_3"/>
        <skos:exactMatch rdf:resource="https://gcmdservices.gsfc.nasa.gov/kms/concept/d81fc4e3-c0b4-4205-82b2-ef2161c169a3"/>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>
  
    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Instrument/VIIRS">
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">VIIRS</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Visible/Infrared Imager Radiometer Suite</skos:altLabel>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/SNPP"/>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/NOAA-20"/>
        <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/SNPP"/>
        <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/NOAA-20"/>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Visible Infrared Imaging Radiometer Suite (VIIRS) instrument collects visible and infrared imagery and global observations of land, atmosphere, cryosphere and oceans. Currently flying on the Suomi NPP satellite mission, VIIRS generates many critical environmental products about snow and ice cover, clouds, fog, aerosols, fire, smoke plumes, dust, vegetation health, phytoplankton abundance and chlorophyll. VIIRS will also be on the JPSS-1 and JPSS-2 satellite missions. More Information: https://www.jpss.noaa.gov/viirs.html Mass: Approximately 252 kilograms Average Power: 191 W Development Institutions: Raytheon Company VIIRS Sensor Lead: Bruce Guenther (NOAA) Purpose: To collect measurements of clouds, aerosols, ocean color, surface temperature, fires, and albedo. Group: Instrument_Details Entry_ID: VIIRS Group: Instrument_Identification Instrument_Category: Earth Remote Sensing Instruments Instrument_Class: Passive Remote Sensing Instrument_Type: Spectrometers/Radiometers Instrument_Subtype: Imaging Spectrometers/Radiometers Short_Name: VIIRS Long_Name: Visible-Infrared Imager-Radiometer Suite End_Group Group: Associated_Platforms Short_Name: SUOMI-NPP Short_Name: JPSS-1 End_Group Group: Spectral_Frequency_Information Wavelength_Keyword: Visible Number_Channels: 7 Spectral_Frequency_Coverage_Range: 0.412 μm - 0.746 μm End_Group Group: Spectral_Frequency_Information Wavelength_Keyword: Near Infrared Number_Channels: 2 Spectral_Frequency_Coverage_Range: 0.865 μm End_Group Group: Spectral_Frequency_Information Wavelength_Keyword: Infrared &gt; Reflected Number_Channels: 6 Spectral_Frequency_Coverage_Range: 0.7 μm - 2.25 μm End_Group Group: Spectral_Frequency_Information Wavelength_Keyword: Infrared &gt; Thermal Number_Channels: 7 Spectral_Frequency_Coverage_Range: 3.74 μm - 12.013 μm End_Group Online_Resource: https://www.jpss.noaa.gov/viirs.html Creation_Date: 2009-03-17 Group: Instrument_Logistics Instrument_Owner: USA/NOAA Instrument_Owner: USA/NASA End_Group End_Group</skos:definition>
        <rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="https://www.wmo-sat.info/oscar/instruments/view/viirs"/>
        <skos:exactMatch rdf:resource="https://gcmdservices.gsfc.nasa.gov/kms/concept/dd7c719e-5767-4ceb-b83a-66c1401dab4a"/>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>
  
    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Instrument/AVHRR_3">
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">AVHRR/3</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Advanced Very High Resolution Radiometer / 3</skos:altLabel>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Metop-A"/>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Metop-B"/>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Metop-C"/>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/NOAA-18"/>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/NOAA-19"/>
        <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Metop-A"/>
        <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Metop-B"/>
        <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Metop-C"/>
        <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/NOAA-18"/>
        <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/NOAA-19"/>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">[ Text Source, ESA Meteorological Missions Homepage, http://www.esa.int/esaLP/SEM9VEG23IE_LPmetop_0.html ] The Advanced Very High Resolution Radiometer (AVHRR/3) is one of the complement of American instruments provided by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to fly on MetOp-A, B and C. The AVHRR/3 scans the Earth surface in six spectral bands in the range of 0.58 - 12.5 microns. It provides day and night imaging of land, water and clouds, measures sea surface temperature, ice, snow and vegetation cover. The AVHRR/3 is a six-channel imaging radiometer that detects energy in the visible and infrared (IR) portions of the electromagnetic spectrum. The instrument measures reflected solar (visible and near-IR) energy and radiated thermal energy from land, sea, clouds, and the intervening atmosphere. The instrument has an instantaneous field-of-view (IFOV) of 1.3 milliradians providing a nominal spatial resolution of 1.1 km (0.69 mi) at nadir. A continuously rotating elliptical scan mirror provides the cross-track scan, scanning the Earth from ± 55.4° from nadir. The mirror scans at six revolutions per second to provide continuous coverage. The instrument provides spectral and gain improvements to the solar visible channels that provide low light energy detection. Channel 3A, at 1.6 microns, provides snow, ice, and cloud discrimination. Channel 3A will be time-shared with the 3.7-micron channel, designated 3B, to provide five channels of continuous data. An external sun shield and an internal baffle have been added to reduce sunlight impingement into the instrument’s optical cavity and detectors. Group: Instrument_Details Entry_ID: AVHRR-3 Group: Instrument_Identification Instrument_Category: Earth Remote Sensing Instruments Instrument_Class: Passive Remote Sensing Instrument_Type: Spectrometers/Radiometers Instrument_Subtype: Imaging Spectrometers/Radiometers Short_Name: AVHRR-3 Long_Name: Advanced Very High Resolution Radiometer-3 End_Group Group: Associated_Platforms Short_Name: METOP Short_Name: METOP-A Short_Name: METOP-B Short_Name: NOAA-19 Short_Name: NOAA-18 Short_Name: NOAA-17 Short_Name: NOAA-16 Short_Name: NOAA-15 End_Group Group: Spectral_Frequency_Information Wavelength_Keyword: Near Infrared Number_Channels: 3 Spectral_Frequency_Coverage_Range: 0.58 μm - 1.64 μm Spectral_Frequency_Resolution: 1.09 km End_Group Group: Spectral_Frequency_Information Wavelength_Keyword: Infrared &gt; Thermal Number_Channels: 3 Spectral_Frequency_Coverage_Range: 3.55 μm - 12.5 μm Spectral_Frequency_Resolution: 1.09 km End_Group Online_Resource: http://www2.ncdc.noaa.gov/docs/klm/html/c3/sec3-1.htm Online_Resource: http://www.esa.int/esaLP/SEM9VEG23IE_LPmetop_0.html Online_Resource: http://www.eumetsat.int/Home/Main/Satellites/Metop/Instruments/SP_2010053153142514 Online_Resource: http://database.eohandbook.com/database/instrumentsummary.aspx?instrumentID=403 Sample_Image: http://goespoes.gsfc.nasa.gov/poes/instruments/images/enlarged_avhhr.jpg Creation_Date: 2008-07-22 Group: Instrument_Logistics Instrument_Owner: USA/NOAA Instrument_Owner: USA/NASA End_Group End_Group</skos:definition>
        <rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="https://www.wmo-sat.info/oscar/instruments/view/avhrr_3"/>
        <skos:exactMatch rdf:resource="https://gcmdservices.gsfc.nasa.gov/kms/concept/87c44e15-54c8-407d-a881-8035a2d5512b"/>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>
  
    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Instrument/MERSI-2">
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">MERSI-2</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Medium Resolution Spectral Imager -2</skos:altLabel>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/FY-3D"/>
        <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/FY-3D"/>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en"></skos:definition>
        <rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="https://www.wmo-sat.info/oscar/instruments/view/mersi_2"/>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>
  
    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept rdf:about="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Instrument/MODIS">
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">MODIS</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Moderate-resolution Imaging Spectro-radiometer</skos:altLabel>
        <sosa:isHostedBy rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Terra"/>
        <skos:broader rdf:resource="http://vocab.met.no/mmd/Platform/Aqua"/>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">The Moderate Resolution Imaging Spectroradiometer (MODIS) is a multi-disciplinary, keystone instrument on Aqua and Terra, providing a wide array of multispectral, daily observations of land, ocean, and atmosphere features at spatial resolutions between 250 m and 1000 m. Approximately 40 data products are produced from the MODIS data. Data are distributed not only through the EOS Data and Information Service (EOSDIS) Distributed Active Archive Centers (DAACs) at Goddard Space Flight Center, the EROS Data Center in Sioux Falls, South Dakota, and the National Snow and Ice Data Center (NSIDC) in Boulder, Colorado, but also via over 100 Direct Broadcast (DB) stations distributed world-wide. Key MODIS Facts Heritage: AVHRR, HIRS, Landsat TM, and Nimbus-7 CZCS Instrument Type: Medium-resolution, multi-spectral, cross-track scanning radiometer; daylight reflection and day/night emission spectral imaging Swath Width: 2,300 km at 110 degree (&amp;#177;55 degree) Coverage: Global coverage every 1 to 2 days Spatial Resolution: 250 m, 500 m, 1 km Dimensions: 1.04 m x 1.18 m x 1.63 m Mass: 229 kg Thermal Operating Range: 268 &amp;#177; 5 K Power: 162.5 W (average), 225 W (peak) Duty Cycle: 100% Instrument Nadir IFOV: 250 m (2 bands), 500 m (5 bands), 1,000 m (29 bands) Polarization Sensitivity: 2% from 0.43 &amp;#181;m to 2.2 &amp;#181;m and &amp;#177;45 degree scan Signal-to-Noise Ratios: From 500 to 1100 for 1-km ocean color bands at 70 degree solar zenith angle NEDt: Typically &lt; 0.05 K at 300 K Absolute Irradiance Accuracy: 5% for wavelengths &lt; 3 &amp;#181;m and 1% for wavelengths &gt; 3 &amp;#181;m Group: Instrument_Details Entry_ID: MODIS Group: Instrument_Identification Instrument_Category: Earth Remote Sensing Instruments Instrument_Class: Passive Remote Sensing Instrument_Type: Spectrometers/Radiometers Instrument_Subtype: Imaging Spectrometers/Radiometers Short_Name: MODIS Long_Name: Moderate-Resolution Imaging Spectroradiometer End_Group Group: Associated_Platforms Short_Name: TERRA Short_Name: AQUA End_Group Group: Spectral_Frequency_Information Wavelength_Keyword: Visible Number_Channels: 10 Channels Spectral_Frequency_Coverage_Range: 0.4 - 0.7 &amp;#181;m End_Group Group: Spectral_Frequency_Information Wavelength_Keyword: Infrared &gt; Reflected Number_Channels: 10 Channels Spectral_Frequency_Coverage_Range: 0.75 - 3 &amp;#181;m End_Group Group: Spectral_Frequency_Information Wavelength_Keyword: Infrared &gt; Thermal Number_Channels: 16 Channels Spectral_Frequency_Coverage_Range: 3.0 - 14.5 &amp;#181;m End_Group Online_Resource: https://modis.gsfc.nasa.gov/ Online_Resource: https://modis-land.gsfc.nasa.gov/ Online_Resource: https://lpdaac.usgs.gov/dataset_discovery/modis/modis_products_table Online_Resource: https://atmosphere-imager.gsfc.nasa.gov/ Online_Resource: https://nsidc.org/data/modis/index.html Online_Resource: https://ladsweb.modaps.eosdis.nasa.gov/ Online_Resource: https://oceancolor.gsfc.nasa.gov Online_Resource: https://mcst.gsfc.nasa.gov/ Online_Resource: https://modis.gsfc.nasa.gov/data/ Online_Resource: https://modis.gsfc.nasa.gov/data/dataprod/index.php Sample_Image: httpa://modis.gsfc.nasa.gov/about/images/modisComponents.jpg Creation_Date: 2007-04-16 Group: Instrument_Logistics Data_Rate: 6.2Mbps (average), 10.5 Mbps (daytime), 3.2 Mbps (nighttime) Instrument_Start_Date: 2002-06-25 Instrument_Owner: USA/NASA End_Group Group: Instrument_Logistics Data_Rate: 6.2Mbps (average), 10.5 Mbps (daytime), 3.2 Mbps (nighttime) Instrument_Start_Date: 2000-02-24 Instrument_Owner: USA/NASA End_Group End_Group</skos:definition>
        <rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="https://www.wmo-sat.info/oscar/instruments/view/modis"/>
        <skos:exactMatch rdf:resource="https://gcmdservices.gsfc.nasa.gov/kms/concept/2878f334-35dc-47a7-a3ae-8c5da1adccd3"/>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

  </skos:Collection>
</rdf:RDF>
