<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#">
  <!-- 
Prepared by Øystein Godøy, METNO/FOU, 2012-10-23 
First very simple description...
Use hidden to identify common mis spellings...
Check what is available through GCMD and ICES, potentially also INSPIRE.
Ideally a geoJSON identification of a polygon providing boundaries should be
added in the future.
Should these keywords indicate hierarchy? The Barents Sea is part of the
Arctic etc...
-->
  <skos:Collection rdf:about="https://wiki.met.no/metamod/vocabularies/Areas">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Geographical areas</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Controlled vocabulary to be used in METAMOD context to describe geographical areas. This should be related to GCMD science keywords through altLabel. The definition should contain a unique specification of the area. Historically, METAMOD started out with ocean areas only. Open issues remain on how to best classify land regions.</skos:definition>
    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Arctic</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Central Arctic</skos:altLabel>
        <skos:altLabel xml:lang="en">Central Arctic</skos:altLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to indicate that data are located in the Arctic. The definition of the Arctic may however differ as no unique definition exists. In MetaMod context this should refer to data located nortwards of the Arctic Circle, i.e. 65 degrees North.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Barents Sea</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to indicate data located in the Barents Sea. The definition of this ocean area may differ as no unique definition exists. In MetaMod context this is usually used to refer to observations within or above the sea. It can also be used to identify observations at islands, but such would preferably be indicated with Svalbard if belonging to these islands.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Beaufort Sea</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to indicate data are located in the Beaufort Sea. The definition of this ocean area may differ as no unique definition exists. In MetaMod context this is usually used to refer to observations within or above the sea.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Chukchi Sea</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to indicate data located in the Chukchi Sea. The definition of this ocean area may differ as no unique definition exists. In MetaMod context this is usually used to refer to observations in the ocean, but can also be used for observations on islands in the area.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Denmark Strait</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to indicate data located in the Denmark Strait. That is the strait between Iceland and Greenland, effectively separating the Greenland and Iceland Seas. It is used to identify oceanic observations.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">East Siberian Sea</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en"></skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Fram Strait</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to indicate data located in the Fram Strait. That is the strait between Svalbard and Greenland, separating the Arctic Ocean from the Greenland Sea. It is primarily used to identify oceanic observations.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Greenland Sea</skos:prefLabel>This is used to identify data from the area between the Fram Strait and the Denmark Strait, between Greenland and the Mohn-Sverdrup ridge or the Norwegian Sea. It is primarily used for oceanic observations but may also include observations at Jan Mayen.<skos:definition xml:lang="en">
        </skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Iceland Sea</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to identify data from the area west and south of the Denmark Strait. It is also used to identify observations from Iceland unless marked as Arctic.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Kara Sea</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to indicate data from ocean, atmosphere and islands in the Kara Sea.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Laptev Sea</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to indicate data from ocean, atmosphere and islands in the Laptev Sea.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Nordic Seas</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to identify the combined area of the Norwegian and the North Seas. It is mainly used to identify oceanic data.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Northern Hemisphere</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is a general classification to be used when the more specific definitions are not suitable.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">North Sea</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to identify data from the North Sea. Primarily it is used for oceanic observations as well as observations from platforms. The North Sea is located south of the Norwegian Sea, bordered by the Faroe-Shetland area and the Norwegian coast, all the way down to the continent.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Norwegian Sea</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to identify data from the North Sea. Primarily it is used for oceanic observations as well as observations from platforms. It is bordered by the Greenland Sea, the Barents Sea, the North Sea and the Faroe-Iceland ridge.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

    <!-- This class could potentially be removed and replaced by the
    Arcic or similar. -->
    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">White Sea</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to indicate data from ocean, atmosphere and islands in the White Sea. 
        </skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>

  </skos:Collection>
</rdf:RDF>
