<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#">
  <!-- 
Prepared by Øystein Godøy, METNO/FOU, 2012-10-23 
First very simple description...
Use hidden to identify common mis spellings...
-->
  <skos:Collection rdf:about="https://wiki.met.no/metamod/vocabularies/Operational_Status">
    <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Operational Status</skos:prefLabel>
    <skos:definition xml:lang="en">Controlled vocabulary to be used in METAMOD context to describe operational status of datasets handled. This is used in filtering of the information. Typically scientific datasets are generated without a temporal perspective and review process. The review process of scientific products is publications in refereed journals or in data citation papers. Experimental, Pre-Operational and Operational are concepts supported by institutions with a committment for a specific delivery over time.</skos:definition>
    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Operational</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to tag datasets that are continously being evaluated and validated. The production of the data is under the responsibility of an authority and follows a review and documentation process. Operational data are generated on a continous basis with a temporal perspective.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>
    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Pre-Operational</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to describe data that are under review for becoming the next operational delivery. It is usually produced continously, but not necessarily distributed to users not specifically. It covers the intermediate step between Experimental and Operational.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>
    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Experimental</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to describe data that belongs to a development and production chain that provides operational data. It is the first step in the process of becoming operational.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>
    <skos:member>
      <skos:Concept>
        <skos:prefLabel xml:lang="en">Scientific</skos:prefLabel>
        <skos:definition xml:lang="en">This is used to describe purely scientific products, i.e., products generated through scientific projects and usually with a limited temporal perspective.</skos:definition>
      </skos:Concept>
    </skos:member>
  </skos:Collection>
</rdf:RDF>
